Here, only the silent survive.
The Killing Fields is a drama, history, war film directed by Roland Joffé.
New York Times reporter Sydney Schanberg is on assignment covering the Cambodian Civil War, with
the help of local interpreter Dith Pran and American photojournalist Al Rockoff.
When the U.S.
Army pulls out amid escalating violence, Schanberg makes
exit arrangements for Pran and his family.
Pran, however, tells Schanberg he intends to stay in Cambodia to help cover the
unfolding story — a decision he may regret as the Khmer Rouge rebels move in.
Sydney Schanberg, played by Sam Waterston.
Dith Pran, played by Haing S. Ngor.
Al Rockoff, played by John Malkovich.
Jon Swain, played by Julian Sands.
Military Attaché, played by Craig T. Nelson.
U.S. Consul, played by Spalding Gray.
The Killing Fields is a 1984 British biographical drama film about the Khmer Rouge regime in Cambodia, which is
based on the experiences of two journalists, Cambodian Dith Pran and American Sydney Schanberg.
It was directed by Roland Joffé and produced by
David Puttnam for Goldcrest Films.
Sam Waterston stars as Schanberg, Haing S.
Ngor as Pran, and John Malkovich as Al Rockoff.
The adaptation for the screen was written by Bruce Robinson; the musical score was written by Mike
Oldfield and orchestrated by David Bedford; and the costumes were designed by Judy Moorcroft.
The film was a success at the box office and an instant hit with critics.
At the 57th Academy Awards it received seven Oscar nominations, including Best
Picture; it won three, most notably Best Supporting Actor for Haing S.
Ngor, who had no previous acting experience, as well as
Best Cinematography and Best Editing.
At the 38th British Academy Film Awards, it won eight BAFTAs, including
Best Film and Best Actor in a Leading Role for Ngor.
In 1999, the British Film Institute voted The Killing Fields the
100th-greatest British film of the 20th century.
It is now seen as one of the greatest films of all time.
The film explores themes of journalist, vietnam,
cambodia, civil war, based on novel or book.
The tone is dark and emotional.